<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | notes from the sandbox]]></title>
  <link href="http://erichannell.com/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://erichannell.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-07T19:16:56+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://erichannell.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Hannell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[News Is Changing]]></title>
    <link href="http://erichannell.com/blog/2014/04/29/news-is-changing/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-29T22:50:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://erichannell.com/blog/2014/04/29/news-is-changing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the way we consume news changes so does our relationship with news itself.</p>

<p>There are now an estimated <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_number_of_mobile_phones_in_use">97 cell phones per every 100 people on this planet</a>. Not all of them are smartphones, but with <a href="http://www.cnet.com/uk/news/mozillas-25-firefox-os-its-real-and-it-works/">Mozilla working on a $25 model</a>, the day when everyone that wants a smartphone owns one isn&rsquo;t far off.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>In the U.S., the population consuming news digitally is still low compared to TV, but it is a rapidly growing group:<p></p>
<img src="http://www.people-press.org/files/2013/08/2-Main-Source-for-News.png" alt="news" /></p>

<p>Smartphones brought the internet to our pockets and an infinity of articles to our eyeballs. You might not always be in front of a TV or newspaper, but if you are like most people, you&rsquo;ll never be far from your phone. Also, as screen sizes grow, people will likely only consume more news on their devices.</p>

<p>Maybe because they face infinite choice, consumers are also less loyal than ever. Many  prefer sites that aggregate content (like Google News, the Drudge Report or the Huffington Post) for daily news fixes. Consumers of digital news are more interested in the story than the organisation that broke it. Also, while some reporters have a loyal following, they often take their followers with them when they leave an organisation.</p>

<p>Twitter has become the go-to place to get breaking news and apps like Circa keep users updated with alerts and updates to the stories that interest them.</p>

<p>The majority of people that own devices also consume news on those devices:<p></p>
<img src="http://www.journalism.org/files/legacy/u29/PJ_12_09_17_tabletNews-report_01_1.png" alt="digital" /></p>

<p>It will be fascinating to see where these trends lead us.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
